William Francis Gray Swann Papers 1903-1962 Mss.B.Sw1
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Articles and lectures, 14.5 Linear feet
  - Atomic particles and their activities, March 16, 1949 (Box 51)
    Franklin Institute Stated Meetings
  - Atomic particles of physics, and what they do (Box 51)
    Sent to Jackson for Walt Disney
  - Atomic power, October 22, 1940 (Box 51)
    Radio address before N.Y. Herald-Tribune forum at the Waldorf-Astoria
  - Atomic structure (Box 51)
    - Atomic structure (Box 51)
    - Chapter A. Introduction (Box 51)
    - Chapter B. Series in Spectra (Box 51)
    - Chapter C. Wave Mechanics, General Schroedinger Equations System of Uniform Rectilinear Motion, Electricity and Magnetism (Box 51)
    - Chapter C. Simple Bohr Theory for Circular Orbits (Box 51)
    - Chapters C pp 21-39, E pp 35-47 (Box 51)
    - Chapter D (Mss) (Box 51)
    - Chapter D. Dynamics (Box 51)
    - Chapter D. Dynamics Copy #3 (Box 52)
    - Chapter E. Theory of Relativity (Box 52)
  - Atomic world. Radio address, December 27, 1935 (Box 52)
    Given at American Institute of the City of New York
  - Attempt to detect a corpuscular radiation of cosmic origin (Box 52)
  - Attempt to detect magnetic field as result of rotation of copper sphere at high speed (Box 52)
  - Autobiography (Box 52)
  - Automatic apparatus for recordings, history of shower phenomena (Box 52)
  - Avoidance of collision at sea (Box 52)
  - B - 29 Flights, 1951 (Box 52)
  - Balancing harmonies in Solenoid (unfinished) (Box 52)
  - Balloons, Causes and prevention of fires in., 2 folders (Box 52)
  - Bartol Research Foundation (Box 52)
    - Bartol Research Foundation (Box 52)
      Mon. and Weds. Group, notes, problems, etc
    - Colloquium, 1938 (Box 52)
    - Facilities (Box 52)
    - For Forum Magazine (Box 52)
    - History (Box 52)
      Sent to NSF
    - History prior to World War II (Box 52)
    - Investigations in Progress at Bartol (Box 52)
      Purdue University
    - Report on Work of the Bartol Research Foundation, 1940-1941 (Box 52)
    - Work (Box 52)
      Sent to Hollingsworth
  - Bases and allied matters (Box 52)
  - Bearing of the Earth's internal magnetic permeability upon the self and mutual induction of coils... (Box 52)
  - Bearing of the earth's size upon changes in its magnetization (Box 53)
  - Bearing of the earth's size upon changes in its magnetization (Mss Copy) (Box 53)
  - Bi-Metallic strip (unfinished) (Box 53)
  - Binding energy and mass defect (Box 53)
  - Binding energy and mass defect and allied matters in relation to the quantum theory (Box 53)
  - Blue shield (Box 53)
  - Book reviews by Swann, 3 folders (Box 53)
  - Bragg, William. Obituary (Box 53)
    Appeared in APS Yearbook
  - Brain twisters (Box 53)
  - Brookhaven memoranda (Bartol) (Box 53)
  - Calculation of steady state temperature distributions (Box 53)
  - Calculations (unfinished) (Box 53)
  - Calculations based on the law of inverse squares (Box 53)
  - Calibration curves (Box 53)
  - Can modern science harmonize physics and biological phenomena?, September 1939 (Box 53)
    Congress of Biophysics, Cosmics, etc.; New York
  - Carbon filament, problem (Box 53)
  - Cello. Franklin Institute Television, June 21, 1939 (Box 54)
  - Certain application of physical principles to playing of musical instruments (Box 54)
  - Certain fundamental mathematical theorems (Box 54)
  - Certain matters concerning scaling in magnetron (Box 54)
  - Characteristic phenomena in which atoms and molecules play a part (Box 54)
  - Characteristics of atom bursts produced by cosmic rays (Box 54)
  - Charging of bodies. Memorandum concerning (Box 54)
  - Civil Defense (Box 54)
    - Lecture I. Ionization phenomena (Box 54)
    - Lecture II. Outline of Atomic theory (Box 54)
    - Lecture III. Instruments and measurements (Box 54)
    - Lecture to those involved in making radioactive survey (Box 54)
  - Classical electrodynamics and the conservation of energy (Box 54)
  - Clock paradox, Feb. 24, 1961 (Box 54)
    Applied Physics Lab., Silver Springs, Maryland
  - Clock paradox and paradox of identical twins, etc (Box 54)
  - Cockcroft, John - Citation and introduction (Box 54)
  - Coefficients of capacity and induction, Folder 1 (Box 54)
  - Coefficients of capacity and induction, Folder 2 (Box 54)
    Electricity and magnetism lecture course
  - Colloquium memorandum (Box 54)
  - Comments on fellows problems, and scientific memoranda, Folder 1 (Box 54)
  - Comments on fellows problems, and scientific memoranda, Folder 2 (Box 54)
  - Comments on unidentified paper (Box 54)
  - Comments regarding Prof. Stewart's letter, Dec. 8 (Box 54)
  - Complete conversion of absorbed heat into work (Box 54)
  - Compton, A. H., Appreciation as President of AAAS (Box 54)
  - Concepts in quantum theory, 2 folders (Box 54)
  - Concerning conservation of energy and related laws (Box 54)
  - Concerning demonstrations in physics (Box 55)
  - Concerning nuclear reactor for Philadelphia area (Box 55)
  - Concerning potential successors at Bartol, 2 folders (Box 55)
  - Concerning Rockets. December 16, 1957. (Box 55)
  - Concerning small particles of iron (Box 55)
  - Concerning the possibility of obtaining electrical power from atmospheric-electric phenomena (Box 55)
  - Conditions for identical orbits in the case of two charged particles (Box 55)
  - Conduction of heat, Measurement of mass of gas using... from heated wire (Box 55)
  - Conduction, Electronic and electrolytic... (unfinished) (Box 55)
  - Conquest of the atom. Recorded lecture. First paper (Box 55)
  - Consequences of assumption of single primary component in cosmic radiation (Box 55)
  - Conservation of direction in the impact of high-energy particles (Box 55)
  - Conservation of momentum (Box 55)
  - Considerations pertaining to the splitting of oscellograms (unfinished) (Box 55)
  - Contemporary theories of light (Box 55)
  - Control of Neutron Density, memoranda, 1953 (Box 55)
  - Cornerstone laying. Remarks by Swann (Box 55)
  - Corpuscular theory of the primary cosmic radiation (Box 55)
  - Cosmic radiation (Box 55)
  - Cosmic ray (Box 55)
    - Acquirement of cosmic ray energies, January 27-30, 1960 (Box 55)
      At American Physical Society
    - Conference, Duke University, Nov. 30, 1953 (Box 55)
  - Cosmic rays (Box 55)
    - Acquirement of cosmic ray energies (Box 55)
    - Anniversary issue, Journal, Franklin Institute, 1951 (Box 55)
    - Are Cosmic Rays Bullets or Waves? (Box 55)
    - B-29 experiments, 1948 (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Rays (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Rays [General Lecture] (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Rays (unfinished notes) (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Rays, For American Weekly, June 14, 1951 (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Rays (As presented to Brooklyn Academy), March 15, 1957 (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Rays. Written for Dr. Clyde Fisher (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Rays (As presented to Hostess Committee), Nov., 12, 1936 (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Rays. Physical Society Progress Reports, Vol 10. (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Rays. (As Presented at Wellesley), March 11, 1940 (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Rays. For WFIL-TV (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Rays and Nature of Field in Magnetized Iron (Swann and Lees) (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Rays are International. Radio address over WROL (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Ray Conference, Duke University, Nov. 30, 1953 (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Ray Conference, Moscow, 1959; 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Ray energies from stellar bodies (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Ray Ionization. For APS, April 22, 1933 (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Ray Measurements in the Stratosphere (Box 55)
    - Cosmic Ray Observations in stratosphere (sent to National Geographic Society), August 21, 1936 (Box 56)
    - Cosmic Ray Showers below Sea Level (Box 56)
    - Cosmic Ray Symposium, Idaho Springs, June 22, 1949 (Box 56)
    - Cosmic Ray Variations at high altitudes - meteorological variations (with Forbes) (Box 56)
    - Critical survey of certain theorems (Box 56)
    - Demonstration Lectures (Box 56)
    - Electromagnetic Acceleration of Cosmic Rays, 1955 (Box 56)
    - Encyclopedia Americana, 1952 (Box 56)
    - Explorers Club Presentation, Jan. 17, 1948 (Box 56)
    - General approach to cosmic ray energy, Sept. 4-15, 1961, Jan 1962 (Box 56)
    - Lead absorption of cosmic rays (Box 56)
      Comments on Gill's paper
    - Mechanism of acquirement of cosmic ray energies by electrons (Box 56)
    - National Geographic Society, Feb. 21, 1947 (Box 56)
    - Notes concerning Cosmic Ray Theory, Zenith Angular Distribution (Box 56)
    - Notes [unidentified] (Box 56)
    - Nuclear disintegrations (Box 57)
    - Orbits (unfinished notes) (Box 57)
    - Processes involved in electromagnetic acceleration of particles to Cosmic Ray Energies (Box 57)
      Extended version, Moscow Papers
    - Cosmical electric field (Box 57)
  - Counter memorandum, January 29, 1934 (Box 57)
  - Counters for stratosphere flights (Box 57)
  - Creativity in the sciences, October 11, 1956 (Box 57)
    RCA, Camden
  - Culture in this age of science, 1937 (Box 57)
    Inauguration of Pres. George Keith Chalmers, Kenyon College
  - Current potential relation, to Dr. Danforth (unfinished) (Box 57)
  - Curves (unfinished) (Box 57)
  - Cygnatron (note by W. F. G. Swann) (Box 57)
  - Davis, W. and Sons. Receipt (Box 57)
  - Density of liquid, Measurement (Box 57)
  - Derivation of electromagnetic equations (Box 57)
  - Design of galvanometer and thermocouple system (Box 57)
  - Destruction and reconstruction of matter (Box 57)
  - Detection of cavities by radioactive techniques Memorandum. Detonating systems, Memorandum (Box 57)
  - Detection'of U-235 (Box 57)
  - Detonating Systems, Memo (Box 57)
  - Direction of approach of cosmic ray electrons in equatorial plane. Director's skeleton report, March 18, 1942 (Box 57)
  - Director's report, March 18, 1942 (Box 57)
  - Dissipation function in the dynamics of continuous media (Box 57)
  - Distribution curves (Box 57)
  - Distribution of cosmic ray paths in a vertical cylinder (Box 57)
  - Dorsey, N. Ernest. Proposed new term in radioactivity (Box 57)
  - Drexel Institute 60th anniversary panel discussion (Box 57)
  - Drop rotating in magnetic field (Box 57)
  - Dynamics (Box 57)
  - Dynamics and measurements, Jan. 21, 1957 (Box 57)
    Haverford College
  - Dynamics for Temple (Box 57)
  - Dynamics of the electron (Box 57)
  - Earth as a magnet and generator of electric charge (Box 57)
  - Earth's electric and magnetic fields (Box 57)
  - Earth's electric charge (abstract) (Box 57)
  - Earth's magnetic field, etc. (Box 57)
  - Effect of absorption on cosmic ray azimuthal asymmetry (unfinished) (Box 57)
  - Effect of certain monochromatic ultra-violet radiation on Euglena (Box 58)
  - Effect of galactic rotation on intensity of cosmic radiation (Box 58)
  - Effect of primary cosmic ray energy upon Stoss production (with Cowie) (Box 58)
  - Effect of soft x-ray on Euglena (unfinished) (Box 58)
  - Effect of world conditions upon the development of physical science, July 7, 1942 (Box 58)
    Institute of Physical Affairs, Charlottesville, Va.
  - Efficiency of thermocouple system as generator of power (Box 58)
  - Ehrenfest dispute (Box 58)
  - Einstein's theory (Box 58)
  - Einstein's theory of gravitation (Box 58)
  - Eisenbud's class. Memorandum (unfinished) (Box 58)
  - Eisenbud's lectures (notes) (Box 58)
  - Eksergian, Rupen (Box 58)
  - Elastic vibrations (Box 58)
  - Electrets (Box 58)
    - Electrets (Box 58)
    - Electrets (unfinished) (Box 58)
    - Case of charged density distribution vs. electret behavior (Box 58)
    - Concerning, conduction current during the formation of electrets (Box 58)
    - Electrets, Space charged distribution for the steady state (Box 58)
    - Fundamentals in behavior of electrets (New York, AIEE), Jan. 23, 1953 (Box 58)
    - Memorandum on electrets (Box 58)
    - On certain matters pertaining to electrets (Box 58)
    - Research studies on electrets, Feb. 15, 1951-May 15, 1951 (Box 58)
    - Second Memorandum on electrets (Box 58)
    - Space charge electrets vary with position (Box 58)
    - Statement regarding abstracting electrets material (Box 58)
  - Electricity and magnetism. Lecture course. (Box 58)
  - Electrodynamic theory of Piezo-electric oscillations (abstract) (Box 58)
  - Electrodynamics and mutual annihilation of positive and negative electricity (Box 58)
  - Electrodynamics and optics (Box 58)
  - Electrodynamics, Part I. Book (Box 59)
  - Electrodynamics, Part II. Book (Box 59)
  - Electromagnetic equations with magnetic charges (Box 59)
  - Electromagnetic induction and relative motion... (Box 59)
  - Electromagnetic induction in matter of astronomical dimensions (abstract) (Box 59)
  - Electromagnetic material (misc.) (Box 59)
  - Electromagnetic theory notes, 5 folders (Box 59)
  - Electrometer potentiometer (Blueprint and picture, too) (Box 59)
  - Electron orbits (unfinished) (Box 60)
  - Electron theory. Chapter I (Box 60)
  - Electronic puss (Box 60)
  - Electrostatic and magnetic potentials of shells, etc (Box 60)
  - Electrostatic deflection of cosmic radiation (with Danforth) (Box 60)
  - Electrostatic devices, Memo (Box 60)
  - Electrostatics (Box 60)
  - Elementary nuclear physics for engineers. Lecture and subsidiary notes (Box 60)
  - Elementary text book (Box 60)
  - Elements for speeches (Box 60)
  - Employment of a system of two pliotrons for amplification..."A scheme for submarine detection" (Box 60)
  - Employment of the Einthoven galvanometer in connection with "A scheme for submarine detection" (Box 60)
  - Energy conversion without large moving parts. Memorandum (Box 60)
  - Energy in a magnetic field, Memorandum (Box 60)
  - Energy of a system of shells (Moore School) (Box 60)
  - Energy theorem (Box 60)
  - Engineer and scientists, Sept. 4, 1952 (Box 60)
    Chicago, Centennial of Engineering
  - Engineering and pure science (Box 60)
  - Entropy and probability (Box 60)
  - Equation (Box 60)
  - Equipartation of energy and radiation theory (abstract) (Box 60)
  - Equivalence of the different methods of expressing the magnetic field (Box 60)
  - Errors in physics (for Jastrow) (Box 60)
  - Expansion of spheres of electrons (Box 60)
  - Experiences of an amateur musician, Dec. 12, 1947 (Box 60)
    Bethlehem, Pa.
  - Experiment bearing on the theory of metallic conduction (Box 60)
  - Experiment concerning origin of 2nd hump in Rossi curve (abstract) (Box 60)
  - Experimental basis for the laws of electrodynamics (Box 60)
  - Experiments on the penetratory radiations at Pikes Peak and Colorado Springs (Box 60)
  - Expression of appreciation to those who have been responsible for organizing the conference (Box 60)
  - Expressive intonation, Dec. 1950 (Box 60)
    MTNA, Washington, D.C.
  - Fatigue in metals, March 24, 1955 (Box 60)
    National Bureau of Standards, conference
  - Field of a point charge moving along x axes with velocity (Box 60)
  - Filrad Thursday class (Box 60)
  - Five minute speech, March, 31, 1938 (Box 60)
    Luncheon talk before Philadelphia Music Club
  - Fluctuations in proportional counters (Box 60)
  - Force equation of electrodynamics (Box 61)
  - Form and feeling in music (Box 61)
    Student paper sent to Philadelphia Music Academy
  - Fourier series, March 18, 1955 (Box 61)
    Humorous dinner speech, American Physical Society, Baltimore
  - Frankford arsenal memorandum on training in tracer technique (Box 61)
  - Franklin Institute projects (Box 61)
  - Frontiers and new theories (Box 61)
  - Frontiers and new theories, Jan. 15, 1944 (Box 61)
    Explorers' Club Annual Dinner
  - Fundamental bricks of atomic structure (Box 61)
  - Fundamentals of classical electrodynamics (Box 61)
  - Fundamentals of classical electrodynamics. Preface to 3rd book (Box 61)
  - Fundamentals of electrodynamics (Box 61)
  - Fundamentals of electrodynamics Part I (Box 61)
  - Fundamentals of electrodynamics (Pub: Journal Franklin Inst), Nov, 1928 (Box 61)
  - Further evidence for a single component in the cosmic radiation (Box 61)
  - Future of music in these times, June 3, 1942 (Box 61)
    Zecker-Hahn Commencement address
  - Galileo Galelei (Box 61)
  - Galvanometer problem (Box 61)
    Sent to Chatterjee
  - Galvanometer, vibrating string (Box 61)
  - Gap in an iron ring, Problem of field in (Box 61)
  - General dynamics considerations -- Piezo-electric oscillations, etc. (Box 61)
  - General statement. Depart of applied mathematics (Box 61)
  - Generalization of electrodynamics, consistent with relativity (Box 61)
  - Goodyear Tire and Rubber Company (Box 61)
  - Gravitation Lecture (Box 61)
  - Gravitation. Can there be a shield for gravity?, Aug. 27, 1960 (Box 61)
    Research Foundation, New Bowton, N.H.
  - Gravitation. Matter, anti-matter, end (Box 61)
  - Hall effect, Possible method for measuring and suggested method (Box 61)
  - Heat flow along and heat generated in a bar (Box 61)
  - Heavy charged particles as primary cosmic rays (Box 61)
  - Highlights of science for 1935 (Box 61)
  - Highlights of science for 1935, Jan. 8, 1936 (Box 61)
    N.Y. Electric Society
  - Hoffman Stosse (with Street) (Box 61)
  - Horizons Unlimited, 22 folders (Box 61-62)
  - Humorous material (Box 62)
  - Ideas (Box 62)
  - Ignition of gasoline by electric discharge (Box 62)
  - Impact of solids. Memorandum (Box 62)
  - Impact problem. Memorandum (Box 62)
  - Implications of principle of indetermination, Jan. 11, 1949 (Box 62)
    State College
  - Impulse generated on stooping electrons in ring (Box 62)
    Sent to Pata
  - Impurities in cathode base metals (Box 62)
  - Inelastic scattering -- Differential cross sections, etc. (Box 62)
    Problem for Rasmussen
  - Instruction for Mr. Levian (Box 62)
  - Internation Critical Tables (Box 62)
  - Introduction of Stad, Moennig, and Bostelmann at Franklin Institute, Feb. 11, 1937 (Box 62)
  - Intuition (Box 62)
  - Intuition in mathematical physics, Dec. 29, 1955 (Box 62)
    Atlanta
  - Investigating temperature -- effects of impact between armor piercing core and armor, 3 folders (Box 62)
  - Ionization (unfinished) (Box 62)
  - Ionization by high energy charged particles. (Swann-Bram). (Box 62)
  - Ionization fluctuations (unfinished) (Box 62)
  - Is science destroying civilization?, Feb. 20, 1939 (Box 62)
    Contemporary Club
  - Jeans, James -- Speech in honor of (Box 62)
  - Kelly, Mary Isabel (comp. and trans.) (Box 62)
    - German Pegasus, Twelve selections (Box 62)
    - German workmen poets. 12 selections (Box 62)
  - Kelvin, Lord. Presentation of bust to Smithsonian Institution (Box 62)
  - Kinetic theory of gasses (Box 63)
  - Latitude effect at high latitudes and high altitudes (Box 63)
  - Latitude effect. (Box 63)
  - Latitude variation of vertical cosmic ray intensity at high a latitudes (Box 63)
  - Law of inverse squares (Box 63)
  - Laws of nature (Washington Academy of Sciences), Oct. 17, 1940 (Box 63)
  - Least time (Box 63)
  - Lecture 1 (in England?) (Box 63)
  - Lecture No. 18 (Box 63)
  - Lectures to high school students (Box 63)
  - Lens for cosmic ray electrons (Box 63)
  - Letter to Dr. J. Heidmann (Box 63)
  - Life in these times, Feb. 11, 1943 (Box 63)
    Sigma Xi, Temple University
  - Lodge, Oliver... Address (Box 63)
  - Logarithmic derivative of psi function (Box 63)
  - M.K.S. system of units - Significance of dielectric constant permeability, etc (Box 63)
  - Macroscopic equations (Box 63)
  - Macroscopic equations general (Box 63)
  - Macroscopic equations, simplified (Box 63)
  - Magnetic bending cosmic rays, etc. (unfinished) (Box 63)
  - Magnetic deviation of secondary cosmic ray particles (unfinished) (Box 63)
  - Magnetic deviations due to a submarine (Box 63)
  - Magnetic domains, Concerning Bozorth (Box 63)
  - Magnetic field deflection (Box 63)
  - Magnetic field due to currents (Box 63)
  - Magnetic field measuring device (Box 63)
  - Magnetic fields due to currents and the action of currents on each other (Box 63)
    Electricity and Magnetism course
  - Magnetic particles, Researches on (Box 63)
  - Magnetized iron, Nature of field in (unfinished) (Box 63)
  - Magnets, etc. Problems (unfinished) (Box 63)
  - Magnets, Lattice problem (unfinished) (Box 63)
  - Magnitudes in world of molecules (Box 63)
  - Man s place in the Universe, April 10, 1958 (Box 63)
    Wainwright House
  - Man's place in the Universe, May 8, 1961 (Box 63)
    Rochester, N.Y.
  - Mars-equivalent path length as a function of zenith angle (Box 64)
  - Mass, Theory of (unfinished) (Box 64)
  - Mass-energy relation (Box 64)
  - Mass-energy relation in Quantum theory (Box 64)
  - Materialism and the universe (Boston), March 19 and 21, 1961 (Box 64)
  - Mathematical theory of magnetism, electricity, and the electron theory. Mathematical introduction to electricity and magnetism lecture (Box 64)
  - Matters pertaining to the background of modern quantum theory (Box 64)
  - Matthay Association address (Box 64)
  - Maximization of z= (S2 6)/(Ke plus Kg) (Box 64)
  - Maxwell's equations (Box 64)
  - McCarty, L. E. Thesis (Box 64)
  - Mean life considerations in relation to curvature of cosmic ray paths in a magnetic field (Box 64)
  - Mean life, Determination of (unfinished) (Box 64)
  - Mean life, Determination of, as function of energy (Box 64)
  - Measure, Angular distribution - G. M. Counters (Box 64)
  - Measurement of mass of gas conduction of heat from heated wire (Box 64)
  - Measurements of the specific ionization of cosmic rays by Swann and W. E. Ramsey (unfinished) (Box 64)
  - Measurements of variation of residual ionization in air with pressure at different altitudes (Box 64)
  - Mechanism of acquiring cosmic ray energies by electrons (Box 64)
  - Memoranda concerning cathode project (Box 64)
  - Memo concerning doctor's theses (Box 64)
  - Memos, scientific (Box 64)
  - Memos on Cosmic rays, etc. (Box 65)
  - Memo on dosimeter problems (Box 65)
  - Memo on Gill's work (Box 65)
  - Memo on insurance and allied matters (Box 65)
  - Memo on Mr. Simons activities at Bikini (Box 65)
  - Memo on navy contracts (Box 65)
  - Memo on new building, March 10, 1958 (Box 65)
  - Memo on P. E. Rouse's "Viscoelastic properties of Polymer Solutions" (Box 65)
  - Memo on the mathematical theory of high velocity impact (Box 65)
  - Memo on theoretical physicist (general) (Box 65)
  - Memo on visit of Irving Rowe (Box 65)
  - Memo on disposal of parts of defective apparatus (Box 65)
  - Memo for Mandeville. Cleaning up Power Law Matter (Box 65)
  - Memo giving advice in research (Box 65)
  - Memo on absorption coefficient of lead (Box 65)
  - Memo on atmospheric electricity: objects, instruments, and methods (Box 65)
  - Memo on Brazil expedition (Box 65)
  - Memo on Philipoff's measurements (Box 65)
  - Memo on solid state (Box 65)
  - Memo Rifling and rotating bands (Box 65)
  - Memo. Loss of energy deflection of neutrons from walls (Box 65)
  - Mesotron mean lifetime as function of momentum (Box 65)
  - Mesotron memorandum (unfinished) (Box 65)
  - Mesotron, Determination of... rest lifetime (Box 65)
  - Mesotrons - A test for the reality of mean life in... (with a note to Dr. Woo) (Box 65)
  - Meteorological correction (Box 65)
  - Method of acquirement of cosmic ray energies (Box 65)
  - Method of measuring specific heats, etc. (Box 65)
  - Miller, Dayton C. Obituary (Box 65)
  - Minnesota. exams, 1918-1923 (Box 65)
  - Miscellanea (Box 65)
    - C. Casals Music Festival, "Chinese book, Chebeague Island, Coffee concerts (Box 65)
    - H. Henisch, Hill,Jr (Box 65)
    - M. Medical material (Box 65)
    - O. Oak Ridge school of music, Orchestras (Box 65)
    - P. Publicity (Box 65)
    - S. Sad case of the poor Swan, Soc. of Sons of St. George (Box 65)
    - Addresses, activities, architecture of the Universe (newspaper clippings), Amazing Stories (on Swann), July 1952 (Box 65)
  - Miscellaneous atomic structure (Box 65)